<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Data Science Garage</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Data Science Garage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:13:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>0.0 R Bootcamp intro</title>
      <link>/bootcamp/0.0-bootcamp-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bootcamp/0.0-bootcamp-intro/</guid>
      <description>Bootcamp overviewThe purpose of this self-guided, online Bootcamp is to help get beginners in R started as quickly as possible or to help people with experience refresh their knowledge. There are 3 modules introducing data science skills, including R Programming, traditional statistical analysis, and open science tools. We use R here because it is specifically designed for people with little or no formal programming training, and because it is so good at doing all the things we aim to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>0.0 R Bootcamp intro</title>
      <link>/bootcamp/0.0-bootcamp-intro.utf8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bootcamp/0.0-bootcamp-intro.utf8/</guid>
      <description>Bootcamp overview The purpose of this self-guided, online Bootcamp is to help get beginners in R started as quickly as possible or to help people with experience refresh their knowledge. There are 3 modules introducing data science skills, including R Programming, traditional statistical analysis, and open science tools. We use R here because it is specifically designed for people with little or no formal programming training, and because it is so good at doing all the things we aim to do.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>