<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R Misc on Data Science Garage</title>
    <link>/categories/r-misc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R Misc on Data Science Garage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r-misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Misc 01 R Basics</title>
      <link>/misc-r/01-r-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/misc-r/01-r-basics/</guid>
      <description>R Tips and tricks on a variety of topics  Overview
 The great thing about data analysis, statistics, programming, and R, is that there is always something new to learn.
 Tools for creating evidence from data are constantly evolving and changing. These days, the advancement is faster than ever. This page presents some tips and tricks on a variety of topics to make the journey easier.
 Contents</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Misc 02 R Data files</title>
      <link>/misc-r/02-data-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/misc-r/02-data-files/</guid>
      <description>Reading and working with data files in R  Overview
 The hardest part of starting to use R, is learning how to read in your data file
 This page introduces the bare basics of working with data sets with multiple variables of different types. Data frames are the most convenient data objects in R. Others you will run across are matrices and lists, which are also described here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Misc 03 Graphing and tables</title>
      <link>/misc-r/03-graphs-tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/misc-r/03-graphs-tables/</guid>
      <description>Critique bad graphs as a sport
 Graphing and tables as outputs  Overview
 The finest data analysis can easily be wrecked by bad graphs
 This page introduces the basics of practice, and good practice, in producing graphs and tables in R. In the examples below, x and y are numeric variables in the hypothetical data frame, mydata. A and B are categorical variables (factors or character variables) identifying different groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Misc 04 Sample size and power</title>
      <link>/misc-r/04-sample-size-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/misc-r/04-sample-size-power/</guid>
      <description>If power analysis were an athlete, it would be a sumo wrestler
 Defending your sample size  Overview
 Many scientific studies lack sufficient statistical power, failing to defend their sample size
  Contents
4.1 Data simulation to explore sample size
4.2 Power and sample size calculation
4.3 Suggested reading
 This page provides a brief overview on two methods to defend your sample size. First, methods in data and sample size simulation are examined.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>