<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Statistics on Data Science Garage</title>
    <link>/tags/statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Statistics on Data Science Garage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2.1 Question, explore, analyze</title>
      <link>/bootcamp/2.1-m2-question-explore-analyze/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bootcamp/2.1-m2-question-explore-analyze/</guid>
      <description>Question, explore, analyze (a workflow for data science)  VIDEO 2.1
SCRIPT 2.1 Use this to follow along on this page and for the Practice exercises below.
Optional reference to review key concepts: Danielle Navarro. 2019. Learning Statistics with R
 Overview
 A dataset often comes to the Data Scientist in an imperfect state, possibly incomplete, containing errors, and with minimal description. Likewise, it may contain wonderful knowledge, there to discover.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2.2 Sampling and distributions</title>
      <link>/bootcamp/2.2-m2-sampling-and-distributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bootcamp/2.2-m2-sampling-and-distributions/</guid>
      <description>Sampling and distributions  VIDEO 2.2
SCRIPT 2.2 Use this to follow along on this page and for the Practice exercises below.
Optional reference to reinforce key concepts: Rafael Irizarry. 2020. Introduction to Data Science (Chs 13-16)
 Overview
 I. A curve has been found representing the frequency distribution of standard deviations of samples drawn from a normal population.
II. A curve has been found representing the frequency distribution of values of the means of such samples, when these values are measured from the mean of the population in terms of the standard deviation of the sample…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2.3 Correlation</title>
      <link>/bootcamp/2.3-m2-correlation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bootcamp/2.3-m2-correlation/</guid>
      <description>Correlation  VIDEO 2.3
SCRIPT 2.3 Use this to follow along on this page and for the Practice exercises below.
 Overview
 Most of you will have heard the maxim &amp;ldquo;correlation does not imply causation&amp;rdquo;. Just because two variables have a statistical relationship with each other does not mean that one is responsible for the other. For instance, ice cream sales and forest fires are correlated because both occur more often in the summer heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2.4 Simple linear regression</title>
      <link>/bootcamp/2.4-m2-simple-linear-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bootcamp/2.4-m2-simple-linear-regression/</guid>
      <description>Question, explore, analyze (a workflow for data science)  VIDEO 2.4
SCRIPT 2.4 Use this to follow along on this page and for the Practice exercises below.
 Overview
 &amp;ldquo;The general rule is straightforward but has surprising consequences: whenever the correlation between two scores is imperfect, there will be regression to the mean.&amp;rdquo; - Francis Galton
 One of the most common and powerful tools in the statistical toolbox is linear regression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2.5 T-test</title>
      <link>/bootcamp/2.5-m2-t-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bootcamp/2.5-m2-t-test/</guid>
      <description>T-test (and related questions and tools)  VIDEO 2.5
SCRIPT 2.5 Use this to follow along on this page and for the Practice exercises below.
 Overview
 The t-test and t-distribution are widely considered to be at the very foundation of modern statistic science and they form an important foundation for the practice of statistics. Who would believe they were invented to make great beer better?
 William Sealy Gosset is credited with inventing and applying the idea of the t-test to assist in scientific quality control while working for the Guiness brewery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2.6 1-way ANOVA</title>
      <link>/bootcamp/2.6-1-way-anova/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bootcamp/2.6-1-way-anova/</guid>
      <description>1-way ANOVA (and related questions and tools)  VIDEO 2.6
SCRIPT 2.6 Use this to follow along on this page and for the Practice exercises below.
 Overview
 The analysis of variance is not a mathematical theorem, but rather a convenient method of arranging the arithmetic. R. A. Fisher (via Wishart 1934. Sppl. J. Roy. Soc. 1(1):26-61.)
 Perhaps more so than any other tool, the Analysis of Variance (ANOVA) literally revolutionized the idea of objectivity in using data to produce evidence to support claims.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>